<Document>

  # Electricity

  There a few ways to generate power on the planet, such as:

  ## Portable generators

  JrPacman is the most basic portable generator. It uses welding fuel and generates low-voltage electricity, up to 8kw,
  perfect for powering your small hut. You can use the autolathe to make a board for it, and then build it like any other machine.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorJrPacman" Caption="JRPacman"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorJrPacmanMachineCircuitboard" Caption="JR Pacman board"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeldingFuelTankFull" Caption="Welding fuel tank"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Autolathe" Caption="Autolathe"/>
  </Box>

  Pacman is a more advanced version, capable of generating up to 30 kw in medium or high voltage.
  It uses solid plasma as fuel, and is way more effecient is high-voltage mode.

  The board for it can be crafted in the circuit imprinter. You will need epistemics/science to research the power generation
  technology in order to get access to it. The good news is, your starting structure should already have one pre-built!

  In order to convert the MV/HV electricity in LV, you will need an APC and/or a substation. See below.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorPacman" Caption="Pacman"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorPacmanMachineCircuitboard" Caption="Pacman board"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlasma1" Caption="Sheet of solid plasma"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaOre1" Caption="Plasma ore"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter" Caption="Circuit imprinter"/>
  </Box>

  SuperPacman is a more advanced version, capable of generating up to 50kw in high voltage, and using uranium as its fuel.
  Don't worry though, it's not radioactive.

  It has the same research requirements as Pacman.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorSuperPacman" Caption="Super Pacman"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorSuperPacmanMachineCircuitboard" Caption="Super Pacman board"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UraniumOre1" Caption="Uranium ore"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetUranium1" Caption="Sheet of uranium"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter" Caption="Circuit imprinter"/>
  </Box>

  ## Solars

  While not the most powerful source of energy, solars can still be quite useful.
  They produce less power if there is any solid obstruction in the direction they are facing (such as walls, trees, etc),
  so make sure to clear the surrounding area.

  Building a solar array requires 3 key components:

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SolarPanel" Caption="Solar panel"/>
  </Box>

  Solar panels. Many of them. An array of 12 can produce up to 8 kw of power during daytime, however, the exact power output depends
  on many factors, such as how precisely they follow the sun direction, how much lighting the planet offers, and more.

  You can build one by crafting a solar assembly in the autolathe and then adding glass to it.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SolarTracker" Caption="Solar tracker"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SolarTrackerElectronics" Caption="Solar tracker electronics"/>
  </Box>

  At least one connected solar tracker. It will track the sun and allow you to adjust the orientation of the panels to face it.

  You can build one by crafting a solar assembly and a solar tracker electronics in the autolathe and combining them together.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerSolarControl" Caption="Solar control computer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SolarControlComputerCircuitboard" Caption="Solar control computer board"/>
  </Box>

  A solar control computer. You will need to install it and configure it to track the sun.
  The speed at which the sun rotates varies across rounds, but is usually close to 6°/minute.

  # Power conversion

  There are 3 power types in SS14: low voltage (LV), medium voltage (MV), and high voltage (HV).

  - LV is used for most machines and computers, lightbulbs and doors, and more.
  - MV is used to power certain machines such as emitters and particle accelerators, but is mostly just an intermediate step.
  - HV is used to store power in the SMES, and is also an intermediate step.

  ## HV to MV

  You can convert HV to MV using a substation. Its electronics can be printed in the autolathe and it can be built like any other machine.

  Connected an HV cable from your generators or SMES to the substation, and an LV cable from the substation to APCs or other machines.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SubstationBasic" Caption="Substation"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SubstationMachineCircuitboard" Caption="Substation electronics"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SubstationWallBasic" Caption="Wallmount substation"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallmountSubstationElectronics" Caption="Wallmount substation electronics"/>
  </Box>

  ## MV to LV

  You can convert MV to LV using an APC. Its electronics can be printed in the autolathe and it can be built using the crafting menu.

  An APC can be toggled off and on by anyone with engineering access (or a screwdriver and a crowbar) if maintenance is required.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="APCBasic" Caption="APC"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="APCElectronics" Caption="APC electronics"/>
  </Box>

  # Power storage

  You can store power in the SMES - a large battery. Building one is not necessary, but it is good to have if your power generator
  is expected to fluctuate. A good SMES can power a small colony for at least 20-30 minutes without any power production.

  In order to build one, you will need to print SMES electronics in the autolathe, and then build it like any other machine.
  Make sure to place a cable terminal (craftable using some wires) in front of the SMES, with red wires pointing towards it.
  Connect the cable terminal to your power generators, and the SMES to your main power grid. Voila, you have a power bank!

  You can later upgrade the SMES with better batteries or capacitors to store even more power or output it faster.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SMESBasic" Caption="SMES"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SMESMachineCircuitboard" Caption="SMES board"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
