<Document>

  [head=1]Glimmer Management[/head]

  Glimmer in Space Station 14 represents the amount of noospheric pressure in the world.
  Unlike regular pressure however, the glimmer field is pretty uniform throughout the universe,
  such that glimmer fluctuations on one planet or station may affect the entire solar system.

  Most outside of the Epistemics department will not be tasked with helping manage glimmer,
  however, it can pay to know a thing or two about glimmer if you are a psionic.

  The most obvious way to measure glimmer is to ask Sophia (the glimmer scribe), which can typically be found within or near
  the Epistemics department.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SophicScribe" Caption="Sofia"/>
  </Box>

  This statue will send alerts to the Epistemics department on the current glimmer status,
  but anyone may walk up to it and interact with it for a current status update.

  Epistemics PDAs also contain a pre-installed app that can be used to see the current glimmer level and the glimmer chart.
  You may be able to ask your fellow epistemics members to measure it.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SciencePDA" Caption="Epistemics PDA"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerMonitorCartridge" Caption="Glimmer Monitor Cartridge"/>
  </Box>


  [head=1]Dangers[/head]
  Starting with the basics of why you would want to manage glimmer in the first place.
  If it gets too high, some undesirable things will start to happen,
  and some of those things may even cause a further increase in the glimmer level, causing a destructive cascade.

  Examples include both passive entities like anomalies being generated and certain hostile entities appearing around the station.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGlimmerMite" Caption="Glimmer mite"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGlimmerWisp" Caption="Glimmer wisp"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant" Caption="Revenant"/>
  </Box>

  In order to avoid the most destructive of these things, glimmer should generally be kept under 450 milipsi,
  and if glimmer reaches 1000 milipsi (1 psi), a noospheric collapse may occur, erasing the bonds between souls and vessels,
  and the border between reality and imagination.

  This can lead to a variety of negative consequences ranging from a mass mindswap to complete destruction of reality,
  and must be avoided at all costs.

  [head=1]Benefits[/head]
  What is less obvious is that those who have a connection with the noosphere are more likely to gain psionic powers the higher the noospheric pressure is.
  Noospheric discharges can stun psionics, but will also clear their mental blocks and allow them to gain new psionic powers.

  Oracle will also provide more generous gifts for fulfilling its orders when glimmer levels are high.

  [head=1]Raising Glimmer[/head]
  Glimmer can be raised in a number of ways:

  Firstly, the most common is the use of psionic powers.
  Each psionic user has their own amplification and dampening, which determine the force and control they have over their powers.
  The higher their amplification is, the more powerful are the effects their powers have on the world, but also the more glimmer their usage produces.
  Having more psionic powers generally leads to a higher amplification. Therefore, rogue psionics can be a big threat.

  Secondly, Anomalies and certain other psionic entities, such as glimmer mites, generate a constant stream of glimmer for as long as they are active.
  If glimmer levels are getting high, it may be desirable to get rid of those.

  Thirdly, Extracting research from artifacts increases glimmer, so it's recommended to ensure that xenoarchelogy is on pause when glimmer is too high.
  The standard rate is 1 milipsi of glimmer for each 1 kilopoint of research.

  Finally, an active Glimmer Prober generates glimmer constantly in exchange for research points,
  these expensive objects can be used to generate passive income but should be watched carefully.
  If glimmer level exceeds 500 milipsi, they will start powering themselves with the noospheric energy and become impossible to turn off,
  leading to a dangerous cascade.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerProber" Caption="Prober"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AnomalyBluespace" Caption="Anomaly"/>
  </Box>

  [head=1]Lowering Glimmer[/head]
  There are 4 ways to lower glimmer, the most common is with time.
  Noospheric pressure slowly but constantly loosens over time, so halting all noospheric activity will generally lower the glimmer level.

  The second is by waiting for a noospheric discharge or another noospheric event to occur.
  During those discharges, some of the excess noospheric pressure manifests into a physical entity or energy burst.
  For example, it can create glimmer mites, a revenant, a wisp; perhaps duplicate an existing glimmer prober or cause one to explode.
  All of those effects simultaneously lower the glimmer level.

  The most proactive way is by creating a glimmer drain, which uses power to stabilize the noosphere.
  In order to create it, you will need to insert 5 normality crystals into the glimmer prober frame.

  There are a few ways to acquire normality: oracle can give it as a reward for fulfilling an order,
  you can find it in the form of raw normality ore on the planet surface, or you can use chemistry to synthesize it.
  The latter requires ectoplasm, which can be found inside glimmer mites, revenants, and wisps (you will need to grind those).

  The recipe for synthesizing normality is as follows:

  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker" Caption="Take a beaker"/>
    <Label Text="Add 5 units of ectoplasm"/>
    <Label Text="Add 5 units of ash"/>
    <Label Text="Add 5 units of red blood"/>
    <Label Text="Add 5 units of water"/>
    <Label Text="Add 5 units of liquid plasma as a catalyst"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker" Captain="Heat to 200°C"/>
  </Box>

  Finally, In dire circumstances, when glimmer levels are extremely high, and you need to buy time, you can sacrifice a psionic on the altar.
  This is done by placing someone on the altar and sacrificing them using a sharp object (use the right click menu for this).
  In most cases, this will be considered a murder, so make sure to negotiate it with the command staff first.

  (OOC note: unless you are an antag, OOC consent of the sacrificed person - whether explicit or implicit - is required)

  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarFangs" Caption="Altar"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenKnife" Caption="Sharp object"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
