<Document>

  # Building

  Building houses is essential for survival. Not only do they protect you from potentially dangerous atmospheric fluctuations,
  such as gusts of wind, rains, gas clouds, or perhaps temperature fluctuations and attacks from the wild animals on the planet,
  but they can also serve as a place to securely store items and resources.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallSolid" Caption="Solid wall"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WallWoodLog" Caption="Wooden log wall"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14DoorWoodRoom" Caption="Wooden door"/>
  </Box>

  # Security

  Additionally, you can use a multitool on a door electronics to change its access requirements (currently you have to use the right click menu for this).
  Using this board while constructing a powered airlock creates an airlock with the same access requirements.
  This is useful to create a secure door that can only be opened by a specific group of people, such as security or science personnel.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockServiceLocked" Caption="Airlock"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockServiceGlassLocked" Caption="Glass airlock"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Windoor" Caption="Windoor"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorElectronics" Caption="Door electronics for them"/>
  </Box>

  The access configurator can also be used to change the access restrictions of any locked airlock, door, machine, or computer.
  You can buy it from the EngiVend machine, which in turn can be bought from the cargo ordering console.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AccessConfigurator" Caption="Access configurator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineEngivend" Caption="EngiVend sells them"/>
  </Box>

  # Other craftables

  In addition to what you can build in base SS14, Vulpstation offers a wider variety of craftable structures and items, for example:

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloorDrain" Caption="Floor drain"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BenchSofaCorpMiddle" Caption="Sofa"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Fireplace" Caption="Fireplace"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14CrateFreezer" Caption="Freezer"/>
  </Box>

  Check out the crafting menu for more info!

  # Tips

  While holding a stack of steel, glass, and certain other materials in your hand, you can press Z to open the quick crafting menu.
  It can help you quickly craft certain commonly used things, such as machine/computer frames, pipes, pumps, disposals, walls, windows, and more.
</Document>
