<Document>

  # Planetside Communication

  In space station 14, communication is a key. Planet-side colonies are not an exception to this:
  you must have a way to communicate with your fellow colonists in order to cooperate, get help in case of emergencies, and coordinate your actions.

  At the beginning of the round you won't have many communication mediums available to you, but there are a few key ones:

  ## Handheld radios

  Crafted in an autolathe, bought from a salvage vendor, or received for being a native, this device allows you to chat with your fellow colonists.
  In order to hear what other people are saying, you need to turn the radio on (hold it in your hand and press Z). If you say something while near it,
  the radio will relay your message to every other active radio.

  In a future update you will be able to tune your radio to particular frequencies and mute the microphone without muting the radio itself.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadioHandheld" Caption="Handheld radio"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Autolathe" Caption="Autolathe"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Intercom" Caption="Intercom"/>
  </Box>

  ## Faxes and holopads

  While those can sound like old-fashioned communication devices, they are actually quite useful.

  In order to build them, you need to first use the circuit imprinter to print a circuitboard for them
  (perhaps you'll want to ask your local science/epistemics department for help with that).

  A fax machine allows you to send paper messages to other fax machines. You can change the name of your fax by using a screwdriver on it.
  If you don't have a paper, don't worry - the "print paper" and "copy" buttons let you print as much paper as you wish!

  A holopad allows you to call other holopads and perform a kind of video call with people on the other side.
  Similarly to fax machines, you can change a holopad's name by labelling it with a hand labeller.

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FaxMachineConstructible" Caption="Fax machine"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Holopad" Caption="Holopad"/>
  </Box>

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FaxMachineCircuitboard" Caption="Fax machine board"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HolopadMachineCircuitboard" Caption="Holopad board"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter" Caption="Circuit imprinter"/>
  </Box>

  ## Headsets

  Ah, good old radio. What a shame the planet doesn't have a telecommunication server!

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TelecomServer" Caption="Telecommunication server"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TelecomServerCircuitboard" Caption="Its circuitboard"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetGrey" Caption="Headset"/>
  </Box>

  In order to have a functioning radio in the vicinity of your colony, you will need to build a telecommunication server.
  That will require you to set up an epistemics (science) department and research the A/V communication technology.
  After that you will be able to print its circuitboard in the circuit imprinter and build a telecommunication server machine.
  Once that is done, you will just need to fill the server with whatever encryption keys your heart desires
  (in most cases you'll want at least the common encryption key).

  ## PDA messaging

  This one requires a telecommunication server. Open your PDA and navigate to the "programs" tab.
  There you can find the NanoChat program, which allows you to send messages to other players on the same planet.

  In order to message someone, you need to add them as a contact, or have them message you. To do this, press the "+" button in the top right corner,
  type in their NanoChat ID (you will have to ask the person you want to message for it, and you can find yours next to the "+" button).
  Then you will be able to message that person and have them message you back.

  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PassengerPDA" Caption="Your PDA"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NanoChatCartridge" Caption="Cartridge used to install NanoChat. You probably don't need it"/>
  </Box>

  # Orientation

  Craftable in the autolathe, the station map will display the rough layout of the surface.
  Having a handheld station map on your person is pretty useful. Just remember to charge it!

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldStationMapEmpty" Caption="Station map"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Autolathe" Caption="Autolathe"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
