<Document>
  [color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 5: Roleplay and Characters[/head][/color]

  [color=#a4885c]5.1[/color] You are expected to roleplay, and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay. As such, focusing solely on "winning" (such as greentexting or powergaming) is strongly discouraged. So is questionable behavior unfit for an organized, civilized system and society (such as but not limited to: distribution of highly dangerous items without strict need, emergency or valid motive, casually allowing strangers in your department, casual destruction of station property etc.)

  [color=#a4885c]5.2[/color] Prioritize making the game fun for everyone, not just yourself. Antagonists, security, and command staff are held to a higher standard, especially if their actions are found to be going against this rule. If you are uncertain, ask in AHelp.

  [color=#a4885c]5.3[/color] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player. Also, do keep in mind that while your character may be the main character of your story, they are not the protagonist at the center of everything.

  [color=#a4885c]5.4[/color] Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist (i.e. self-antagging or griefing). Examples may include: random murder, destruction or disruption, stealing of high value items (such as Security weapons or Command items), or intentional sabotage.

  [color=#a4885c]5.5[/color] However, it is allowed to form organized groups separate from the main station if you disagree with them over some matters. However, you are expected to roleplay accordingly, do it in a civilized manner, and not be openly hostile to other groups unless there is a clear reason for you to be.

  [color=#a4885c]5.6[/color] Do not play excessively hostile or provocative characters. Playing a character accurately should never result in rule breaches. Being a major nuisance or a source of major frustration to the crew is not accepted. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval.

  [color=#a4885c]5.7[/color] Follow proper escalation (for example, consider assessing a threat for a second before unloading lethal rounds into it, attempt an arrest with non-lethals before opening fire with lethals on someone). Security roles in particular are asked to mind this rule.

  [color=#a4885c]5.8[/color] Do not loot AFK players, nor round remove their bodies without consent, outside of reasonable exceptions (biomassing previous bodies of cloned players, Security performing their duties, etc, putting long disconnected players into cryosleep.).

  [color=#a4885c]5.9[/color] If, when and where possible, always try to do things in a roleplay-friendly way and keep the roleplay rolling.

  [color=#a4885c]5.11[/color] Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long it doesn't cross the border into unacceptable behavior (self-antag, powergaming, metagaming, etc.) and so long properly and well roleplayed. Examples of acceptable ideas could be, light greytiding, well roleplayed hooliganism, breaking into places with good RP or motive, thievery, or black marketing.

  [color=#a4885c]5.12[/color] When picking the name for a character, give them a believable name (and surname if applicable), or a believable nickname to go by. Do not make obvious references, puns, or plays on words. You may "cosplay" a fictional character, but you cannot be the character. Leeway is given to theatrical roles such as the clown, boxer, and mime; these roles are allowed stage names with some more freedom.
</Document>
