<Document>
  [color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 6: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW[/head][/color]

  [color=#a4885c]6.1[/color] Kinks involving a character pretending to be underage (such as infantilism or ABDL) are not allowed.

  [color=#a4885c]6.2[/color] Any creature and being that is or was not player-controlled (including but not limited to: humanoid NPCs, non-humanoid NPCs, and the corpses of either), is to be considered off-limits for any form of ERP (and roleplay involving controversial, heavy themes).

  [color=#a4885c]6.3[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of controversial, heavy themes and topics that would make most people uncomfortable, must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the theme or topic may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

  [color=#a4885c]6.5[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of "extreme" sexual fetishes must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the fetish may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

  [color=#a4885c]6.6[/color] Active ERP must make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper), unless the area is explicitly sanctioned by admins as a "public ERP area" or is a remote space dedicated to it. Public ERP is allowed, so long it follows this rule and not done in a way that's drawing too much attention or/and forcing others to watch or hear active ERP (for example, going at it full naked on top of the main bar's counter, or exaggerate and go too far with out loud lewd actions to the point it's become active ERP). For ERP involving extreme kinks, the rule before this one must be followed. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to.

  [color=#a4885c]6.7[/color] Do not pollute broadcast (radio, telepathic, ooc) channels with NSFW topics. You are allowed to speak on those topics, but if someone asks you to stop, do so.

  [color=#a4885c]6.8[/color] Do not use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved.

  [color=#a4885c]6.9[/color] While usage of kinks or sex mechanics for for gameplay or non-sexual roleplay purposes is not forbidden per se, usage of them should still not be done in a way that breaches other rules.

  [color=#a4885c]6.10[/color] Interrupting ERP is allowed unless it's done in a malicious way (disturbing people just for the sake of disturbing them).
</Document>
